<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f001">
			<line>My Dear sir</line>
			<line/>
			<line>
				<del>agreeably to your request I should </del>
				<add place="above">
					<del>have</del>
				</add>
				<del> eludicated</del>
			</line>
			<line>Mr Gales <del>algebraic demonstration</del> theorem relative to the value</line>
			<line>of annuity stocks, <add>the worth of</add> which he has demonstrated by an algebraic [process]</line>
			<line>process. I have confirmed by an [algeb] arithmetic computation</line>
			<line>and which you will have inclosed.</line>
			<line/>
			<line>Mr Gale in his second Essay page 72 and in his third Essay</line>
			<line>page 60, posits that he has left [something] a particular unexplained relative</line>
			<line>to the conversion of the debt, without [which] the knowledge of which</line>
			<line>the practical financier would bring a considerable loss on the</line>
			<line>public, the discovery of what this unexplained business is he thinks</line>
			<line>rather improbable.- "unless the subject should be retaken up as far</line>
			<line>back as the postulata in the second section of the first Essay: and</line>
			<line>pursued from thence with an immensity of labors through paths</line>
			<line>that [I have] he as (as he says) purposely passed by in silence" I think I have</line>
			<line>discovered what he alludes to and in the paper No 2. you will</line>
			<line>see [that] it detailed, [both] where it is demonstrated that a considerable loss,</line>
			<line>must necessarily be sustained by the public if the particular is not attended</line>
			<line>to, he has also I [can see] alluded to a particular mode, of making</line>
			<line>the loans that shall be requisite, beyond the amount of the</line>
			<line>revenue, to pay the periodical redemption money, for it is</line>
			<line>evident to me, that if the loans are not properly conducted, the</line>
			<line>public will be so much in the power of the money lenders that they</line>
			<line>[may] rather may insist on a much larger premium than the former</line>
			<line>ought to give. This you will see explained in Number 3d.</line>
			<line/>
			<line>This [reason] [probable] reason which [in probability] deterred Mr Pitt from</line>
			<line>adopting Mr Gales plan has rather to my knowledge been</line>
			<line>given.- [One] has however latterly [answered] to me, and which</line>
		</surface>