<sourceDoc xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hamilton">
		<surface facs="#f001">
			<line>My Dear sir</line>
			<line/>
			<line>
				<del>agreeably to your request I should </del>
				<add place="above">
					<del>have</del>
				</add>
				<del> eludicated</del>
			</line>
			<line>Mr Gales <del>algebraic demonstration</del> theorem relative to the value</line>
			<line>of annuity stocks, <add>the worth of</add> which he has demonstrated by an algebraic [process]</line>
			<line>process. I have confirmed by an [algeb] arithmetic computation</line>
			<line>and which you will have inclosed.</line>
			<line/>
			<line>Mr Gale in his second Essay page 72 and in his third Essay</line>
			<line>page 60, posits that he has left [something] a particular unexplained relative</line>
			<line>to the conversion of the debt, without [which] the knowledge of which</line>
			<line>the practical financier would bring a considerable loss on the</line>
			<line>public, the discovery of what this unexplained business is he thinks</line>
			<line>rather improbable.- "unless the subject should be retaken up as far</line>
			<line>back as the postulata in the second section of the first Essay: and</line>
			<line>pursued from thence with an immensity of labors through paths</line>
			<line>that [I have] he as (as he says) purposely passed by in silence" I think I have</line>
			<line>discovered what he alludes to and in the paper No 2. you will</line>
			<line>see [that] it detailed, [both] where it is demonstrated that a considerable loss,</line>
			<line>must necessarily be sustained by the public if the particular is not attended</line>
			<line>to, he has also I [can see] alluded to a particular mode, of making</line>
			<line>the loans that shall be requisite, beyond the amount of the</line>
			<line>revenue, to pay the periodical redemption money, for it is</line>
			<line>evident to me, that if the loans are not properly conducted, the</line>
			<line>public will be so much in the power of the money lenders that they</line>
			<line>[may] rather may insist on a much larger premium than the former</line>
			<line>ought to give. This you will see explained in Number 3d.</line>
			<line/>
			<line>This [reason] [probable] reason which [in probability] deterred Mr Pitt from</line>
			<line>adopting Mr Gales plan has rather to my knowledge been</line>
			<line>given.- [One] has however latterly [answered] to me, and which</line>
		</surface>
		<surface facs="#f002">
			<line>appears to me of sufficient weight to justify that man is [?]</line>
			<line>for not entering in the business, precisely in the manner</line>
			<line>proposed by Mr Gale, which you will recollect was to estimate</line>
			<line>the value of the new stock on the depreciated value of the</line>
			<line>[the] three per cents sh[ow]ing the mean value of the latter at</line>
			<line>63 1/3, by which the public would share [nearly] or rather</line>
			<line>recover nearly what they had lost by the enormous</line>
			<line>premiums which have been given but such an estimate of the three per cents</line>
			<line>might be considered as taking an undue advantage of the</line>
			<line>creditors, who [ought] would expect [ought] to be paid the nominal capital which</line>
			<line>they received for the money they lent, be the latter more or</line>
			<line>less - Indeed if the conversion was made on the nominal</line>
			<line>capital, the debt in the new stock would be greater, and consequently</line>
			<line>the greater revenue must be [applied] provided for payments</line>
			<line>of the interest, but still the power of the [lending?] fund</line>
			<line>[would] [app????] [from] t the redemption. If [irredeemably?] applied</line>
			<line>would be such, as in about 25 years to superceed the necessity</line>
			<line>of any loans for the payment of the annual tender for</line>
			<line>the redemption. - and thence forward (the revenue which at</line>
			<line>the commencement of the conversion was sufficient for the</line>
			<line>[first] years interest) would be an accumulating [something] [pounds]</line>
			<line>which would always keep the debt within moderate bounds</line>
			<line>nay at any point which prudence and the weal of the</line>
			<line>nation should dictate, even altho wars and their</line>
			<line>attendant expenses should prevail as often as they</line>
			<line>have done in the present century -</line>
			<line/>
			<line/>
		</surface>
		<surface facs="#f003">
			<line>These papers all so clearly evince the propriety</line>
			<line>of borrowing on a high interest, when were it may</line>
			<line>be necessary to borrow money, that I hope every</line>
			<line>future loan to the United States will be made</line>
			<line>on these principles. - and in order that no error</line>
			<line>may be made in the compacts with the lenders</line>
			<line>I have shown the terms which you will find</line>
			<line>[h-N-n] - Ever yours affectly</line>
			<line/>
			<line>P--</line>
			<line/>
			<line>Hon A. Hamilton Esqr</line>
			<line/>
			<line>P.S. whether you shall remain in or resign the Superintendence</line>
			<line>of the treasury department, it seems to me equally</line>
			<line>proper that you should establish the principle on which</line>
			<line>all future loans should be made, such as that the means</line>
			<line>of redemption should invariable be annexed to the loans</line>
			<line>[power] an accumulation of debt will always be</line>
			<line>prevented without additional burthens on the people</line>
			<line>and setting out on this system advantages will accrue</line>
			<line>which no nation having a public debt has ever [had]</line>
			<line>yet experienced. - the credit will be yours and</line>
			<line>posterity will bless your memory for having</line>
			<line>produced a system so replete with salutary</line>
			<line>consequences - once more affectionately yours,</line>
			<line/>
			<line>Ph. Schuyler</line>
			<line/>
			<line>Albany January 5 1793</line>
		</surface>
	</sourceDoc>